<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Github on Peter Warnock</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in Github on Peter Warnock</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterwarnock.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub Copilot 2025</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/github-copilot-2025-update-multi-model-ai-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/github-copilot-2025-update-multi-model-ai-assistant/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="github-copilot-2025"&gt;GitHub Copilot 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Copilot 2025 represents the culmination of years of AI development, transforming from a simple code completion tool into a comprehensive multi-model AI development assistant. This latest version integrates OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s groundbreaking GPT-5, supports multiple AI providers through the Model Context Protocol, and introduces revolutionary features like voice-to-code, visual understanding, and real-time collaboration that fundamentally reshape how developers interact with their code and each other. Built on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s extensive AI research and GitHub&amp;rsquo;s massive code repository, Copilot 2025 sets new standards for AI-assisted software development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GitHub Copilot Original</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/github-copilot-original-ai-pair-programmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/github-copilot-original-ai-pair-programmer/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="github-copilot-original"&gt;GitHub Copilot Original&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Copilot Original represents the pioneering AI pair programmer that launched the AI coding revolution in June 2021. Built on OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s groundbreaking Codex model and developed through the strategic collaboration between GitHub and OpenAI, this tool transformed how millions of developers write code by introducing the concept of AI-powered pair programming directly within popular IDEs and code editors. As the first widely adopted AI coding assistant, Copilot Original set the standard for human-AI collaboration in software development and paved the way for the current generation of AI development tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>