<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React on Peter Warnock</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tags/react/</link><description>Recent content in React on Peter Warnock</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterwarnock.com/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Next.js</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nextjs-react-framework-production-applications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nextjs-react-framework-production-applications/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="nextjs"&gt;Next.js&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next.js has established itself as the de facto standard for building production React applications, developed and maintained by Vercel. Since its initial release in 2016, Next.js has evolved from a simple React framework into a comprehensive full-stack development platform that addresses real-world challenges in web development, including performance optimization, SEO, and developer experience. The framework powers some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest websites and applications, demonstrating its scalability and reliability in enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>v0 by Vercel</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/v0-vercel-ai-coding-agent-web-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/v0-vercel-ai-coding-agent-web-frameworks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;v0 by Vercel represents a paradigm shift in AI-powered web development, specifically engineered for modern web frameworks and the Vercel ecosystem. Launched as Vercel&amp;rsquo;s flagship AI coding agent, v0 combines deep expertise in React, Next.js, and contemporary web technologies with the deployment and performance optimization knowledge that makes Vercel the preferred platform for leading web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="core-features"&gt;Core Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="web-framework-mastery"&gt;Web Framework Mastery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React ecosystem expertise&lt;/strong&gt;: Deep understanding of React, React hooks, context, and advanced patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next.js specialization&lt;/strong&gt;: Native knowledge of Next.js routing, server components, API routes, and edge functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern CSS proficiency&lt;/strong&gt;: Expertise in Tailwind CSS, CSS-in-JS, and responsive design principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TypeScript integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Full support for TypeScript with intelligent type generation and inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="performance-first-generation"&gt;Performance-First Generation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Web Vitals optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: AI-generated code optimized for LCP, FID, and CLS metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bundle size awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: Generates code with minimal impact on JavaScript bundle sizes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge computing patterns&lt;/strong&gt;: Native understanding of Vercel&amp;rsquo;s edge network and serverless functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Automatic implementation of next/image and modern image optimization techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="component-intelligence"&gt;Component Intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic design principles&lt;/strong&gt;: Generates reusable, composable components following best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility compliance&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensures WCAG 2.1 AA compliance in all generated components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Implements semantic HTML and meta tags for search engine visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animation and interactions&lt;/strong&gt;: Creates smooth, performant animations using modern web APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="technical-specifications"&gt;Technical Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;: Web-based interface, VS Code extension, CLI tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Tiers&lt;/strong&gt;: Free tier (100 generations/month), Pro tier ($20/month unlimited), Enterprise custom pricing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Native Vercel deployment, GitHub integration, GitLab support, Bitbucket compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Support&lt;/strong&gt;: RESTful API for programmatic component generation, webhook support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;: Average generation time 2-5 seconds, optimized for production-ready code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: Code processed securely, optional private training for enterprise customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="unique-advantages"&gt;Unique Advantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vercel-ecosystem-synergy"&gt;Vercel Ecosystem Synergy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v0&amp;rsquo;s tight integration with the Vercel platform provides unparalleled advantages. The AI understands Vercel&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure, deployment patterns, and performance optimization techniques, ensuring generated code is not just functional but optimized for Vercel&amp;rsquo;s edge network and serverless architecture from the moment of creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Modern Web Development in 2025</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/posts/modern-web-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/posts/modern-web-development/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="modern-web-development-in-2025"&gt;Modern Web Development in 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web development landscape continues to evolve rapidly. Here are my thoughts on the current state and future directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-component-revolution"&gt;The Component Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Component-based architectures have become the standard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React&lt;/strong&gt; continues to dominate with its ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vue 3&lt;/strong&gt; offers excellent developer experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Svelte&lt;/strong&gt; provides compile-time optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Astro&lt;/strong&gt; brings island architecture to the mainstream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="performance-matters-more-than-ever"&gt;Performance Matters More Than Ever&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Web Vitals are now crucial for SEO:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>