<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Framework on Peter Warnock</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tags/framework/</link><description>Recent content in Framework on Peter Warnock</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:53:37 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterwarnock.com/tags/framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tailwind CSS - Utility-First CSS Framework</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/tailwind-css-utility-first-css-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 21:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/tailwind-css-utility-first-css-framework/</guid><description>Tailwind CSS is a utility-first CSS framework that provides low-level utility classes to build custom designs without leaving your HTML, enabling rapid UI development.</description></item><item><title>Nuxt</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nuxt-vuejs-framework-universal-applications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nuxt-vuejs-framework-universal-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nuxt has emerged as the premier framework for building universal Vue.js
applications, transforming the single-file component experience into a
full-stack development platform. Originally created to solve the challenges of
server-side rendering with Vue.js, Nuxt has evolved into a comprehensive
framework that handles everything from development to production deployment.
Built on Vue.js fundamentals and enhanced with modern web development best
practices, Nuxt enables developers to create fast, SEO-friendly, and
maintainable applications with minimal configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Next.js</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nextjs-react-framework-production-applications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/tools/nextjs-react-framework-production-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Next.js has established itself as the de facto standard for building production
React applications, developed and maintained by Vercel. Since its initial
release in 2016, Next.js has evolved from a simple React framework into a
comprehensive full-stack development platform that addresses real-world
challenges in web development, including performance optimization, SEO, and
developer experience. The framework powers some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest websites
and applications, demonstrating its scalability and reliability in enterprise
environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>