<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on Peter Warnock</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on Peter Warnock</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alpha Ad Ops</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/alpha-ad-ops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/alpha-ad-ops/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="alpha-ad-ops---rapid-prototype-development"&gt;Alpha Ad Ops - Rapid Prototype Development&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha Ad Ops is a proof-of-concept advertising operations platform developed as a rapid prototype to demonstrate full-stack development capabilities and modern SaaS architecture patterns. The project was built from concept to deployment in a single day based on prospect requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prototype showcases the ability to quickly translate business requirements into a functional SaaS application using modern Laravel ecosystem tools. The platform demonstrates multi-tenant architecture, admin panel development, and cloud deployment capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>YouSong</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/yousong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/yousong/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="yousong---ai-scripture-music-generator"&gt;YouSong - AI Scripture Music Generator&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouSong is an AI-powered application that generates children&amp;rsquo;s scripture-based songs, built during the Gloo AI Hackathon 2025. The project demonstrates rapid full-stack development using cutting-edge AI tools and modern web technologies to create an engaging educational music experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed as part of FaithTech OC/SoCal Chapter team for the Gloo AI Hackathon, YouSong enables users to create custom children&amp;rsquo;s songs with scripture-based lyrics through AI assistance. The application combines modern AI capabilities with user-friendly interfaces to make religious education engaging and creative.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vocabulary Game</title><link>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/vocabulary-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterwarnock.com/portfolio/vocabulary-game/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vocabulary-game---educational-typing-practice"&gt;Vocabulary Game - Educational Typing Practice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary Game is a simple, focused educational application designed to help young children (specifically 5-year-olds) practice typing, spelling, and reading skills. The project demonstrates the practical application of AI-assisted development for creating educational tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This frontend-only application provides an engaging way for children to learn vocabulary through typing practice. The game displays words that the child types, with immediate feedback on submission. It&amp;rsquo;s designed as a personal educational tool for early childhood development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>